<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on @xanderdin</title>
    <link>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on @xanderdin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Who said CI/CD is only for software?</title>
      <link>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/cicd-for-artidea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/cicd-for-artidea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I googled for CI/CD use cases. There is a huge amount
of articles on the subject but all of them are mostly about
how to apply those practices in a software development
environment. Is this the only way of how those practices and
techniques can be used? Certainly not. And here&amp;rsquo;s my example
of applying them in a non-software production.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Pocket Tomtit</title>
      <link>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/my-pocket-tomtit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 20:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/my-pocket-tomtit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bet nobody of previous or current employees of &lt;a href=&#34;http://integral.ua&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Integral&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; company
is able to explain with absolute confidence until now,
why &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=my.pocket.tomtit&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;See All&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; mobile application in Google Play has
&lt;code&gt;my.pocket.tomtit&lt;/code&gt; ID instead of something like &lt;code&gt;ua.integral.seeall&lt;/code&gt;.
But having straight relation to the app, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell some words
about its roots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My LibreCAD enhancements (October 2018 -- March 2019)</title>
      <link>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/my-librecad-enhancements-20190325/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/my-librecad-enhancements-20190325/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is too fast running out of my head the memories of things I was investing
my time and efforts into. So, after glancing on the history of my
pull requests I decided to make a short report on them for the future
remembrance. Most of the things described here are already merged into main
&lt;a href=&#34;https://librecad.org&#34;&gt;LibreCAD&lt;/a&gt; branch, but some (at the moment of writing of this article) are
still remaining as &amp;ldquo;Open&amp;rdquo; pull requests. Hope, they too would be merged soon.
And here is the list of what I have done in the past few
months to the benefits of &lt;a href=&#34;https://librecad.org&#34;&gt;LibreCAD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitLab through Tor</title>
      <link>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/gitlab-through-tor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/gitlab-through-tor/</guid>
      <description>When GitLab.com moved to Google Cloud Platform, which in turn is blocking connections from some places of our planet, I got troubles accessing my repositories and others hosted on GitLab.com. Having Tor Browser at hand, the quickies solution for me was using it for accessing GitLab.com. All I needed was running Tor Browser and telling git to use it as a proxy.
To make it work, first you need to tell git to use https for remote repository access (if not already configured so).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if I lubricate my &#34;wheel&#34;?</title>
      <link>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/lets-lubricate-the-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 20:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/lets-lubricate-the-wheel/</guid>
      <description>As I related in my previous article, I got a sudden urge to automate my process of preparation of drawings. Automatic enumeration &amp;ndash; perfect, but now I need to prepare those sheets for printing somehow.
These days my main tool for drawing is LibreCAD. When I was choosing it, one of the criterias among others was certainly its freeness and open sources. And at this time the advantage of open source was shown in its full strength.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if I reinvent the &#34;wheel&#34;?!</title>
      <link>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/lets-reinvent-the-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 22:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/lets-reinvent-the-wheel/</guid>
      <description>Olga, my wife is a professional artist and an interior designer. She&amp;rsquo;s using brushes, paints and pencils in a perfect way. But when it comes to a computer the matters become a little bit worse. Nevertheless, she mastered a couple of graphical applications and even such a big &amp;ldquo;monster&amp;rdquo; for 3D modeling as Blender!
But for the interior design neighther drawing a picture nor even building a 3D model is quite enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healing the freezing of Jiayu G2F phone</title>
      <link>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/healing-the-freezing-of-jiayu-g2f-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 14:04:58 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderdin.github.io/en/post/healing-the-freezing-of-jiayu-g2f-phone/</guid>
      <description>I ordered a Jiayu G2F WCDMA phone with 1Gb RAM and 4Gb ROM at Aliexpress. The phone is pretty cool but it has a very disappointing problem - it freezes very often without any visible reason. Searching on the web revealed that this problem pertains to the whole model and not exclusively to my device. I purchased the phone for my daughter and she liked it very much, so we didn&amp;rsquo;t want sending it back to seller.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>